<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jaitl's blog</title><link>https://jaitl.pro/</link><description>Recent content on Jaitl's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 12:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaitl.pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Estimate My Tasks</title><link>https://jaitl.pro/post/2021/05/08/task-estimation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://jaitl.pro/post/2021/05/08/task-estimation/</guid><description>When a task is simple, estimating isn’t a problem but when the task is complex the problem arises. Sometimes I have to estimate complex tasks to measure the sprint time or other activities.
Occasionally my boss asks me why I estimated a task for N hours/days so I have an explanation. In my opinion, the best explanation is a sub-tasks list where each sub-task has a lead time.
My requirements for a task estimation:</description></item><item><title>How AWS AI Services Can Help You Improve Your Foreign Language</title><link>https://jaitl.pro/post/2021/04/26/aws-foreign-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 12:12:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://jaitl.pro/post/2021/04/26/aws-foreign-language/</guid><description>AWS provides several Artificial Intelligence (AI) services. With AI services, you could implement some useful AI things: image and video analysis, document analysis, text to speech or speech to text translation, and so on. However, those AWS services can be used not only for enterprise applications but for your self-development applications.
We are interested in three AI services now:
Polly — text to speech service. It generates audio by text.</description></item><item><title>Working With ClickHouse From Spring Data Using MySql Driver</title><link>https://jaitl.pro/post/2021/04/16/clickhouse-spring-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 12:12:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://jaitl.pro/post/2021/04/16/clickhouse-spring-data/</guid><description>Some time ago I got a task to write a service that inserts data into ClickHouse. My team uses Kotlin and Spring Framework so I decided to try Spring Data JDBC as ORM framework for ClickHouse. After some research, I found that ClickHouse has a MySql interface. Thus, probably, Spring Data JDBC is able to communicate with ClickHouse using MySql driver.
Unfortunately, Spring Data JDBC doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with ClickHouse out of the box thought MySql driver.</description></item></channel></rss>